<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

	<properties>
		<title>The Busy Developer's Guide to the NeuClear ID API</title>
		<author email="pelle@neubia.com">Pelle Braendgaard</author>
	</properties>

	<body>
		<section name="Introduction">

            <h3>Scope</h3>
            <p>
                This document describes in Example form the usage of the NeuClear ID API. The Document is not intended as
                an implemntation document or a strict API definition. The current final API Specifications can be found in the
                <a href="apidocs/index.html">Project Java Docs</a>.
            </p>
            <h3>Purpose</h3>
                <p>
                    The main purpose of the NeuClear ID API is to provide a simple framework and API for building applications
                    using a Public Key Infrastructure (PKI).
                </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Creating an Identity">
            <p>
                All messages (<a href="apidocs/org/neuclear/id/SignedNamedObject.html">SignedNamedObjects</a> in NeuClear lingo)
                in NeuClear ID must be signed by an <a href="apidocs/org/neuclear/id/Identity.html">Identity</a>. So to get started we
                must first create a new Identity.
            </p>
            <p>
                The easiest way to get started is to use the neuclear-id-uber.jar from a command line.
                We need to have the following ready:
            </p> 
            <ul>
                <li>The Name</li>
                <li>A default receiver</li>
                <li>A Public/Private KeyPair</li>

            </ul>
            <p>
                As we first need to create a top level Identity for your domain we will use the name neu://yourdomain.com as the
                Identity name. For now to keep things simple lets use your email address as the default receiver.
            </p>
            <p>
                Now we know the name of our new identity we first need to create our keypair. Sun provides us with a very badly designed
                tool called <a href="http://java.sun.com/j2se/1.4.2/docs/tooldocs/solaris/keytool.html">keytool</a> which we can use to
                create and store our keypair. The NeuClear toolset will provide its own keygeneration tools soon, but for now we've got to do it like this:
            </p>
            <source> <![CDATA[
$ keytool -genkey -keyalg RSA -alias neu://yourdomain.com
Enter keystore password:  #####
What is your first and last name?
  [Unknown]:  neu://yourdomain.com
What is the name of your organizational unit?
  [Unknown]:  Your Domain
What is the name of your organization?
  [Unknown]:  Your Domain
What is the name of your City or Locality?
  [Unknown]:  Panama City
What is the name of your State or Province?
  [Unknown]:  Panama
What is the two-letter country code for this unit?
  [Unknown]:  PA
Is CN=neu://yourdomain.com, OU=Your Domain, O=Your Domain, L=Panama City, ST=Panama, C=PA correct?
  [no]:  yes

Enter key password for <neu://yourdomain.com>
        (RETURN if same as keystore password):
            ]]></source>
            <p>
                This makes our commandline look like this:
            </p>
            <source> <![CDATA[
java -jar neuclear-id-uber.jar neu://yourdomain.com mailto:joeblogs@yourdomain.com
            ]]></source>
            <p>
            </p>
        </section>


	</body>

</document>
