<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

	<properties>
		<title>NeuDist.org</title>
		<author email="pelle@neubia.com">Pelle Braendgaard</author>
	</properties>

	<body>
        <section name="Restructuring of NeuDist">
            <p>
                After much thinking and talking to colleagues I'm restructuring NeuDist and changing it's focus a bit.
                From now on NeuDist will essentially be an XML based PKI and identity system. All the parts of NeuDist that have
                to do with financial clearing and financial systems have been moved to <a href="http://neuclear.org">NeuClear</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
                NeuDist it self will be split into several projects. The first being <a href="/xmlsig/">NeuDist-XMLSig</a>. This is our
                homegrown XML Signature implementation, which will now be carried out as a seperate project.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="New NeuDist Framework Release 0.40">
            <p>
                [October 3rd, 2002] New Release 0.40 is available. This is the first version I would say is ready for live applications.
                You can try out an <a href="http://neudist.org:8080/neudistframework/">example user authentication application here</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
                Because things are moving quite fast right now, I recommend downloading via CVS rather than the distribution files. However if you just want to peak at
                the source code go ahead.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Register Your Own NameSpaces">
            <p>
                We are just getting the infrastructure in place to allow anyone to register namespaces.
                To make it simple for people to understand, you will be able to register permanent namespaces (NEU's) for
                you existing domain names. Initially any request coming from a .com,.net and .org domain will be registered for free.
                To help finance the development we will start charging for non opensource domains soon. Prices will be quite low.
                You can then have any number of namespaces under it. eg. Our domain name neudist.org has a NEU registered as neu://org/neudist.
                </p>
            <p>
                Top level namespaces will be auctioned off. Starting fairly soon. We will initially control neu://neu, neu://test,
                neu://com, neu://org, neu://net . Anything else will be available for sale to help fund our development.
            </p>
            <p>
                You can create your own namespaces in the neu://test free for all namespace. The key for signing new test namespaces
                is in CVS. You can use the org.neuclear.signers.commandline.CommandLineSigner class to create and sign new sub namespaces using
                that key. We are in the process of simplifying this process a bit and wrapping it in shell and .bat file wrappers.
            </p>
        </section>
		<section name="Introduction">
			<p>
				NeuDist is an Open Source software framework written to support the Neubia project for Distributed Transaction Clearing. The initial version is
                written in Java, but we do hope to also provide .NET CLR, Perl and Python implentations of the core functionality soon.
			</p>
            <p>
                The framework will be available to support a wide variety of multi layered financial and non-financial applications. Examples of applications include
                User Authentication, Payments, Auctions, Exchanges, Financial Instruments (Options, Bonds etc). The same basic framework provides the core functionality
                of assurance, authentication and trust for all of these applications. Leaving developers to worry only about the front end functionality of their application.
            </p>
            <p>
                The Core technology is based on XML. With heavy use of the new XML-Signature standard to handle trust and security aspects of the framework.
                We implement a new simple to use PKI (Public Key Infrastructure) to base this trust upon. Communication is done primarily using SOAP.
            </p>
		</section>
	</body>

</document>
