<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>NeuClear - ID</title>
        <author email="pelle@neubia.com">Pelle Braendgaard</author>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Introduction">
            <p>
				NeuClear is an umbrella project to create various technologies to enable a truely distributed future of
                electronic commerce. The NeuClear ID project is a new simplified PKI system to help try to enable the kinds
                applications that people have been talking about the last 10 years, but never got of the ground due to
                usability and logistical reasons.
            </p>
            <p>
                NeuClear ID can be used in web applications, web service and traditional GUI applications. The architecture is
                all about making it simple to use for end users and simple to develop for for coders.
            </p>
            <p>
                For more information about the goals of NeuClear as a whole see the main
                <a href="http://neuclear.org">NeuClear
                Web site</a> as well as the
                <a href="http://neuclear.org/display/neu/The+Two-Minute+NeuClear+Tour">Two-Minute
                NeuClear Tour</a>.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="[29th of April 2004] Milestone Release 0.9">
            <p>
                Panama City, 29th of April, 2004. We are happy to announce
                the milestone 0.9 release of NeuClear ID. Major new features are:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>Completely revamped non hierarchical PKI</li>
                <li>API pretty much stable</li>
                <li>XML format stable</li>
                <li>Much smaller and lighter than version 0.8</li>
                <li>
                    <a href="http://dist.neuclear.org/">New end user based Signing Tool</a>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                The goal of this release has been in particular to make it easier
                for application developers, to start providing support for NeuClear.
                <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=90470">Download it today and join in the NeuClear revolution</a>.
            </p>

        </section>
        <section name="Busy Developer Guide">
            <p>
                We are working on expanding our documentation now. Besides expanding our
                <a href="apidocs/index.html">API Documentation</a>,
                we also now have a
                <a href="bdg.html">busy developers guide</a>. Aimed to get developers started with their own Identities
                quickly and easily.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Road Map">
            <p>
                Our goal is for 1.0 the following release to be fairly polished from a usability standpoint. Our goal is to release this
                in May 2004.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>

</document>
